FIONA CARROLL

SUMMARY

Syracuse University Graduate with a B.A. in Music and a minor in Psychology. Skilled violinist and Master Certified Nutrition and Wellness Coach with the Nutritious Life Studio. I am currently pursuing an award of completion at the UCSD Extension Coding Bootcamp with intention to begin a career in web development.

I have a very diverse background in many different areas. Some include: Administrative duties, Customer service, Childcare, Music, Marketing, Office Management, Public Health, Psychology, Sales, Research, and Website Development.

EXPERIENCE

UCSD EXTENSION CODING BOOTCAMP, SAN DIEGO CA MARCH 2022 -JUNE 2022

- -Currently studying full-time at the UCSD Coding Bootcamp Extension program. Skills include: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Web API's, CSS Frameworks (specifically Bootstrap and Bulma).
- -Link to GitHub Profile showcasing my work: https://github.com/fcarroll12
- -My professional portfolio: https://fcarroll12.github.io/fiona-carroll-professional-portfolio/ #resume
- -Effective Work Scheduler project: A day planner for your work day that is color coded according to time and saves any event or meeting you may insert into local storage. Technologies used include Javascript, jQuery, Local Storage, HTML, and CSS. https://fcarroll12.github.io/effective_work_calendar/
- -Food-Flix: The date-night generator webpage that randomly generates a movie and food to pair. Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, Bulma, Javascript, Web API's, and local storage. https://lgarcia196.github.io/Food-Flix-Project-1/

CREDENTIALING SPECIALIST I, HOST HEALTHCARE, SAN DIEGO CA-AUGUST 2021-OCTOBER 2021

- -Communicated directly with various healthcare workers including other Credentialing Specialists, nurses, and staff across various allied facilities.
- -Ensured all compliance for contracted travel nurses was not expired, up to date, and cleared by facilities including but not limited to: various medical documents, background checks, education and employment verifications, medical certifications, and other highly sensitive information.

- -Ran background checks and uploaded sensitive information to a variety of complex portals used by each facility.
- -Worked closely with Credentialing Specialists and Managers to ensure we met deadlines required by Host Healthcare and allied facilities. This included communication across other departments to help support on-boarding for travel nurses on contract assignments.
- -Used numerous computer software systems such as Adobe and Microsoft to create verification packets, label and edit documents, and miscellaneous medical certifications.

RETAIL SALES ASSOCIATE, SEDONA CLOTHING COMPANY, SEDONA AZ – NOVEMBER 2020- MAY 2021

- -Sales associate for an upscale women's fashion boutique. Provided remarkable customer service.
- -Managed and processed all financial transactions, drove sales, and managed inventory.
- -Trained numerous new employees and from February 2021 to resignation solely managed the boutique full- time.

DESIGN COORDINATOR, THE LIVABLE MOMENT - OCTOBER 2020 - PRESENT

-Improvement consultant for a blog focusing on website development and design. Duties include: Improving monthly analytics using different engagement strategies and design techniques via Wordpress and Bluehost.

ADMINISTRATIVE SUPPORT II, COCONINO COUNTY HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES, FLAGSTAFF AZ – SEPTEMBER 2019- JULY 2020

- -Reviewed and edited cases for rental and utility assistance in both the Coconino County system and the Arizona Department of Housing online system. Determined client eligibility status by reviewing all applications and cases before deeming eligibility to assign to case workers. This included reviewing leases, all households income documents, paystubs, bank statements, and other highly sensitive information.
- -Perform clerical and general office work as the front desk receptionist. Activities have included: search and appropriate disbursal of information to the public and external agencies within guidelines; data entry; direct communications with community members, clients and staff; communications with community via the telephone and mail; handling and filing sensitive and confidential information and documents; routine use as requested of Microsoft tools such as Excel, Word, and Publisher; material proofreading; miscellaneous duties as requested and assigned.

-Duties require maintenance of a polite, nonjudgmental, and patient demeanor with community clients who often are experiencing stressful life situations.

EVENT COORDINATOR, INTERN, COCONINO COUNTY HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES, FLAGSTAFF AZ – JULY 2019- DECEMBER 2019

-Co- developed "Stronger As One:" A mental health and well-being coalition for young adults in Northern Arizona. Interacted directly with teens and young adults as part of education and engagement efforts. Examples included: Stronger As One monthly club meetings, school registrations, school assemblies, school club fairs and parent nights, "Movies on the Square", county fair, girl scouts of northern Arizona B.I.G. event, and the Grand Canyon health fair. Further Participated in the Arizona Department of Health Services Suicide Prevention Goal Council Breakthrough Project Meeting. Represented Stronger As One individually and as part of a team outreach within diverse community settings, meetings, and trainings. Collaboratively communicated and conducted outreach with numerous schools and community-based programs across northern Arizona.

-Co-developed training and outreach materials, such as stickers and PowerPoint slide decks further developing skills with Microsoft Office platforms.

RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT COORDINATOR, INTERN, THE NARBHA INSTITUTE, FLAGSTAFF AZ – JUNE 2018- AUGUST 2018

-Supported development for multiple collaborative initiatives for the Northern Arizona Regional Behavioral Health Authority (NARBHA Institute). Duties included: Researched and summarized Mental Health First Aid efforts in Northern AZ; Investigated and promoted community knowledge for mental health; Planning committee for the October 2018 Stronger as One symposium with over 230 attendees.

CAMP COUNSELOR, THE YMCA OF GREATER BRANDYWINE, PAOLI, PA – JUNE 2016- AUGUST 2016

-KinderCamp Counselor for the YMCA. Developed skills to work with young children in numerous settings. Planned and executed daily activities including music and the arts.

EDUCATION

SYRACUSE UNIVERSITY – BACHELOR OF ARTS IN MUSIC, MINOR: PSYCHOLOGY 2015-2019

- -Attended Syracuse University from August 2015 May 2019. Graduated with honors with a B.A. in Music and a Minor in Psychology.
- -Attended the Strasbourg Conservatoire de Musique in the Spring of 2017. Studied at the conservatory as well as Syracuse University Strasbourg and played with the conservatory's symphonic orchestra.
- -Studied at Kings College London during the Summer of 2017.

SKILLS

Skills include but not limited to: HTML/ CSsS, Javascript, jQuery, Web API's, CSS Frameworks. Proficiency in MS Office Suite Programs; Adobe software; Wordpress/ Bluehost; some knowledge of the French language; Data Entry; Sales and Customer Service; Website development and design; 20+ years of experience in Music. Emotionally intelligent with great problem- solving skills including time management, teamwork, and effective communication.